The rules keep changing.
I've been rehearsing every possible outcome.
Once this thought arises, there is no more room for right or wrong.
I am resolved to sever this flood
so that my soul can break free from mediocrity,
from loneliness and distinction.
One more step and you'll fall into madness.
Don't fall down.
I look towards the top.
Chase !
Refined to perfection.
Never retreat, no matter the danger.
I dare to defy the heavens !
Always overcome the obstacles,
ignite the seas with blood,
bloom through trials and tribulations.
Even the sharpest thorns
will be reduced into ashes.
What is there to fear ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
20 years later
Esteemed listeners, thank you for your support.
Let us pick up where we left off
and speak of the legendary emperor of the Heaven's Path Empire,
His Majesty Wang Ping.
It is said that
for the past several hundred years
the empires of Di Shan, Da Zhou, and Chenyun
held balanced power over the lands.
Heaven's Path Empire
Chenyun Empire
Da Zhou Empire
That was until about 20 years ago.
The ruler of the Di Shan Empire
raised the taxes and exploited the people,
driving the population into misery.
Di Shan Empire
As the saying goes,
heroes rise in turbulent times
and the will of the people is the will of the heavens.
We don't know where this Wang Ping
was born,
nor where he came from.
We just know that during the great famine,
when droughts and floods alternated and people exchanged their children for food,
he arrived in the Di Shan Empire with his wife.
This man
spoke no empty words.
He got things done.
For more than 10 years,
he led by example and saved the people
from their distress.
News of his righteous acts spread from ten to a hundred people,
and his followers grew daily.
He gradually gathered a force not to be underestimated.
They built waterways
and reclaimed the wasteland.
But his most remarkable feat
was leading the people
to repair the dam which caused this whole situation
when it was breached many years ago.
However, a tall tree catches the wind.
His extraordinary acts of kindness
became thorns in the tyrant's side.
This tyrant
was nowhere to be seen to fix the disaster
but traveled at full speed to arrest Wang Ping.
When the news of his arrest spread,
the whole country was in an uproar.
The people's resentment boiled over !
This tyrant was ungrateful !
How unjust it was for Mister Wang...
Indeed !
Esteemed listeners,
did you think Wang Ping was truly unprepared ?
He was not.
He had long anticipated that the tyrant would make such a move.
His act of surrender
was in fact a carefully planned move.
Where is justice ?
Release Mister Wang !
Yes, release him !
The tyrant thought
that killing Wang Ping would intimidate the world
and secure his rule.
But he didn't know that
his tyranny and injustice
lost him the will of the heavens.
He was even less aware
that Wang Ping's followers
had already surrounded him.
Thus fell the Di Shan Empire, which had stood for a thousand years.
The old king died
by the will of the people.
We beg Mister Wang Ping
to follow the will of the heavens
and take the throne to save the people.
We beg Mister Wang Ping to take the throne
and save the people.
Thus,
amidst the cheers of the people,
Wang Ping was crowned
and established his rule over the land.
He named the country
Heaven's Path.
He went from spreading benevolence to win the people's hearts
to anticipating the enemy's moves and placing his own hidden pawns.
And then on the execution ground,
the people's hearts and his hidden pawns were all triggered together.
In this game of chess,
every move was interconnected.
He's truly worthy
of being called a peerless strategist.
In the 5 years since Heaven's Path was established,
Wang Ping governed with diligence
and formed alliances with the Da Zhou and the Chenyun Empire
of mutual non-aggression.
The kingdom was happy and the people at peace.
The scenes of widespread suffering never happened again.
Excellent !
Well said !
Good narration !
In just over 20 years,
Ping'er has indeed become the supreme ruler among mortals.
Heaven's Path has the support of the people
and is growing in strength daily.
The Da Zhou and the Chenyun Empire must be shivering in fear.
This alliance cannot last.
But Heaven's Path has strong soldiers and sturdy horses,
they dare not lightly start a war either.
Royal Palace
Heaven's Path Empire
If they don't fight on the battlefield,
they will naturally find other means.
The elder has strictly ordered
to leave no traces
and no evidence behind.
Da Zhou and Chenyun
have offered the use of the 3 main Spirit Veins for 100 years as payment.
This deal is
pretty good.
Spiritual energy fluctuations ?
Dead...
They're all dead !
Not a single one came back !
How is that possible ?
Da Zhou Emperor
We've never heard of Wang Ping having ties with a cultivation family.
Chenyun Emperor
He rose from obscurity.
How could he...
Investigate !
I want a thorough investigation !
Which family is backing Wang Ping !?
They dared to kill a member of the Qu Family,
this old man will make sure to uncover the one behind him
and exterminate their entire family !
The Ran Family declares that
all cultivators
shall not interfere in the affairs of mortal dynasties.
Those who do
will be exterminated !
Ran...
Ran Family ?
The Zhao Family
proclaims the same prohibition.
Don't let this be an empty warning !
The Sun Family declares
that mortal affairs
belong to the mortal world !
If cultivators cross the line,
the three great families will jointly exterminate them !
Planet Ran Yun's
three great families
were all startled.
Who the hell is behind
this Heaven's Path Empire ?
3 months later
Reporting !
Military Camp
Heaven's Path Empire
We received news of victory from the frontline.
Your Majesty !
The left army has breached Wangbei Pass.
Your Majesty,
the central army is only 300 li from the capital of Chenyun.
Are those the Qilian Mountains ?
Since we are close,
shall we go there to take a look ?
Alright...
I'll go to Qilian Peak to breathe the immortal mist !
Come,
drink your medicine.
Let's go to the back mountain.
That's where
Grandpa Sun is buried.
Sun
Tai's
grave
Qing Yi,
it's been 20 years
since I last saw him.
We can go see him
whenever you wish.
Vast Water City
Master,
the Heaven's Path army has entered the city
but the streets are peaceful.
Apparently,
they didn't harm anyone along the way
nor disturbed them.
Wang
Mansion
Father,
I have not yet fulfilled the wish from back then.
Once your son has accomplished it,
I will come to see you.
At that time,
there are some things
I will need to ask you clearly.
Da Zhou Empire
Heaven's Path has unified the land !
5 years later
Long Live the unification of the four seas !
Long live !
Long, long live !
Finally, this moment has arrived.
Da Zhou
and Chenyun
have submitted to me.
Father,
this era of continuous wars and calamity
has finally come to an end.
You are getting old,
you should drink less wine.
Just one jar for today.
Old Master Wang really has a lonely life.
How time flies...
Ping'er is already 50 years old.
Perhaps he has already
noticed some clues by himself.
Memorials to the throne are endless.
If we could have a son or a daughter,
it would bring some liveliness.
And you wouldn't have to be trapped among these documents all day.
Having you by my side is enough.
As for other things,
I don't force them.
Father,
I have fulfilled your wish.
But why do I feel that
this emptiness in my heart is increasing ?
10 years later
Your Highness,
you mustn't do this !
An empire can't stand for a single day without a ruler !
You can't change my mind.
This vast land of mountains and rivers
was won together by the generals, soldiers, and the people.
I feel at ease
leaving it in your hands.
Qing Yi and I
are tired.
Father,
I'm back.
Wang
Mansion
Young...
Young Master !
What Young Master ?
Don't worry !
Come,
let's go to the back courtyard.
Come, sit down.
The food is still warm.
Dad !
Dad...
Let's eat.
Ping'er,
what do you want to ask me ?
Dad,
I want to know
where I come from.
Alright.
Let me tell you a story.
In a place far, far away,
there is a cultivation planet
called Planet Suzaku.
Heng
Yue
There,
there was a young man.
From the moment he joined an Immortal sect,
he went through many hardships.
He saw all the treachery of the human heart.
The story
was very moving...
Father,
I'm tired.
So...
this is the answer I have waited over 60 years for...
Thousand Illusions Ruthless
Life and Death Domain...
So
I was born of resentment...
Qing Yi,
I'm so tired...
let's find a peaceful mountain village
to settle down in.
Alright.
Wang
Mansion
Perhaps
Mountain village
Planet Ran Yun
you will understand one day.
You need to rest,
eat something first.
Father was right.
In life,
simplicity is best.
If I could choose,
and if there is a next life,
I wish to be with Father
in a small mountain village secluded from the world.
We would live an ordinary, peaceful life.
10 years have passed...
Since you have already understood,
why
don't you go to see him ?
Deep in my heart,
I still had a doubt
that I didn't dare to ask about.
I have a feeling
that perhaps this is
the real reason Father didn't let me cultivate.
The real reason...
After I die,
send me to Father's side.
As for you, you will be free.
But you cannot
forget that during this whole lifetime
No !
you belonged to me.
The underworld...
I will accompany you there.
I don't wish to be a heartless Immortal.
I only wish to be
a sentimental person.
Now this is...
Why are you like this ?
Father once said
that woodcarving
requires you
to use your heart.
Only then
can all the memories
fall upon the carving knife
and melt into the wood carving.
But even after this last one,
I still can't grasp the essence of it.
After I die,
burn these wood carvings
alongside my body.
Father,
I have long since
forgiven you.
Thunder Daoist
Thunder Celestial Hall Messenger
Illusory Yin
I am Sun Xi of the Sun Family.
May Junior know what
brings Senior here ?
I have heard that
someone has been impersonating a Thunder Celestial Temple Messenger.
Have you heard of it ?
As expected,
asking Juniors
was a waste of time.
The Northern Domain of Allheaven has no other messengers.
Just because you know a few thunder spells,
you dared to impersonate someone from the Thunder Celestial Temple ?
A single thread of his Divine Sense
can strike down mortals across the entire planet
while suppressing cultivators !
If I kill him,
I will surely get rewarded.
Wang
Mansion
Could it be that Xu Mu has already left this place ?
That person sure is lucky.
Just now...
an extremely powerful Divine Sense swept through.
Interesting !
A mere mortal
was able to remain conscious under my Divine Sense ?
Note after the ending.
Wang Ping's story to the throne was heavily expanded upon in the donghua. Some notable changes from the novel include the fact Wang Ping didn't rise from rebuilding a village but he instead created a mortal sect called the School of Heaven. His sect grew in power until it rivaled the other countries and conquered them.
When Wang Ping goes back to his hometown, he meets Zhou Ruotong, his childhood love, with her daughter. When they start walking with Qing Yi towards Sun Tai's grave, the little girl says her name.
Wang Ping asked, “Is this your daughter?”
The woman nodded. She turned toward the girl and said, “Call him ‘uncle’. He was your mother’s childhood friend.”
The girl seemed a bit shy. She stood behind her mother and whispered, “Uncle…”
Just after Wang Ping walked several steps, the little girl hiding behind her mother exposed her head and shouted, “Uncle, my name is Xu Nianping!”
Xu being her family name, and Nianping meaning "remember Ping".
Later, when Wang Ping goes back to his father, he doesn't ask about his origins but about his mother specifically.
“Dad, I want to know about my mother…”
It had been more than 60 years since Wang Ping first asked this. He remembered that he had only asked this once, and he saw how crestfallen his father was that time. This was the second time he asked.
After that, when they lived in that small mountain village, we learn that Qing Yi has reached Soul Formation on her own after Wang Lin raised her to Nascent Soul. Her domain is regretless passion. Qing Yi aged herself artificially like Wang Lin.
Go ahead and take a look
on the other side of the mountain.
See if the wind is blowing
across the sea.
A lush tree always grows
from a tender shoot.
That tree shields you
from half of the cold.
The scent of the herbs and the smoke
have drifted away from the stove
whose fire has warmed up
half of your lifetime.
I watch you smile
as you run back to me.
That cry, however,
came out slowly.
I'll take you on a journey through the mortal world,
as autumn fades and spring returns.
A few snowflakes have fallen from the eaves,
I hope this letter finds you well.
I’ll wait for you under the locust tree,
having weathered the storms of our journey so far.
Looking back, the smell of the food
hasn't changed.
Wang
Mansion
Take your time.
I’ll wait for you under the locust tree,
having weathered the storms of our journey so far.
Looking back, the smell of the food
hasn't changed.
Take your time.